# **Michael Becker**

117 Hilltop Drive, Mount Holly Springs PA ♦ 717-829-1597 ♦ mwbecker@andrew.cmu.edu

Web developer focused on delivering technical solutions to business and managerial users. 2+ years developing front end UIs with web frameworks and distributed data sources at US Steel.

#### **EDUCATION**

Carnegie Mellon University — B.S. Information Systems '21

Minor: Human-Computer Interaction

3.78 Cumulative GPA

### **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

**Application Development:** HTML/CSS/JS · VueJs · Flask · Ruby on Rails · Swift

**Data Analytics:** Python · Java · PySpark

**Backend & Misc**: MySQL · Apache Hive · C · Git/Bash · Linux · VSCode · Azure DevOps

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

**Spanish** (Read, Write) • **English** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Full Stack Developer, United States Steel

January 2020 - Present

- Developed software in teams following agile development methodology with daily Scrum calls
- Thoroughly quality tested software prior to deployment to prevent bugs in production
- Used VueJS, HTML/CSS, and Flask to build an end-to-end steel manufacturing delay tracking system
- Performed web crawling for part-ordering cost savings project that helped save procurement division approximately \$250,000 in the 2020 fiscal year
- Assisted teammates in troubleshooting approaches to identify the root cause of problems in software
- Documented and communicated application design standards/guidelines with teammates

## Course Assistant, 67-272 Application Design & Development

January 2020 - Present

- Maintained Gitlab auto-grading server for Ruby on Rails projects
- Used Bash, CI scripting, and Docker to run an automated testing suite

## Web Application Development - Final Project

Spring 2020

 Used ReactJS to create an item selling service for CMU students and integrated Google Maps API to display item locations along with user email authenticated security

# **Application Design and Development**

**Spring 2019** 

- Created a full stack e-commerce web app for a baking company using Ruby on Rails
  - Employed test-driven development software paradigm in phases
- Specifications included employee, order, and customer management functionality

#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

## ScottyLabs, Director of Design

February 2019 – 2020

- Created and distributed event advertisements and recruited new members for design team